

# Osinachi Ogwua WEB DEVELOPER

Friesische Straße 2. 25899 Niebüll Germany

+4915212244022

ossyogwua@gmail.com

https://ossyogwua.github.io/tailwind-portfolio/ https://linkedin.com/in/osinachi-ogwua-03794020a/

## Summary

Detail-oriented web developer, specializing in front-end and back-end web development with proficiency in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Node.js and Express, successfully built three responsive apps from scratch including my portfolio website which includes developing, testing, debugging, and launching. As a professional, I bring a diverse skillset to the table, encompassing teamwork, brainstorming, customer service, all driven by a commitment to practical problem-solving.

## **Web Development Projects**

#### **MyFlix Movie App**

Personal project, CareerFoundry, October- January 2024

- This API provide users with access to information about different movies.
- Users can sign up, update their personal information, and favorite movies list.
- Is non-relational database, user data was stored in MongoDB.
- Created two single-page, responsive front-end apps, one using React and the other using Angular.
- Built with Node.js and Express, using Mongoose to interact with the database.

• Tested the API endpoints with Postman, deployed the API with Render.

#### **Chat App**

Personal project, CareerFoundry, February 2024

- A chat app for mobile devices using React Native.
- The app will provide users with a chat interface and options to share images and their location.
- The app was created be optimized for both Android and iOS devices.
- Developed using Expo and the chat messages were stored with Google Firestore.

- The app page where users can enter their name and choose a background color for the chat screen before joining the chat.
- A page displaying the conversation, as well as an input field and submit button.
- The chat provides users with two additional communication features: sending images and location data.
- Data gets stored online and offline.

#### **Education**

- Full-Stack Wed Development,
  CareerFoundry: May 2023- April 2024
- Bachelor of Science in Political Science

University of Nigeria Nsukka, Graduated 2000

### **Work Experience**

#### **Caregiver Helper**

Pflegediakonie Nordfriesland gGmbH May 2019 – April 2023

- Alloheim Senior Residence April 2017 – April 2019 Administering medication.
- Personal care
- Emotional support
- Communication with patients and family members

#### **Cabin Crew**

Virgin Nigeria Sept. 2005 - June 2009 Air Nigeria Ltd July 2009 - Sept. 2012

- Emergency Evacuations
- Fire Fighting, First Aid
- Crew Resource Management
- Inflight Sales (Duty Free)
- Aviation Security, Inflight Services.

#### **Certificates**

- Full Stack Web Development
- German Language Course B2
  Volks Hoch Schule Husum November
  2015

#### Skills

### **Front End Development**

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL, PowerShell, Express
- Libraries/ Frameworks (React, Redux, Angular, Material, tailwind Bootstrap, jQuery & SCSS
- Json
- Responsive design and modals
- Version Control
- Test-and Behaviour-Driven-Development (unit, integration, acceptance, and end-to-end testing)
- Mobile Apps (React Native, Expo)
- User stories, user flow

### **Back End Development**

- NodeJS & Express
- APIs (JSON, REST, Postman)
- Hosting and Wed (Google firestore, Firebase, Render, GitHub)
- Serverless functions (AWS lambda)
- Relational & non-relational database (PostgreSQL, MongoDB)

#### SOFTSKILLS

- Excellent Teamwork
- Excellent customer service
- Brainstorming
- Quick learning ability.
- Problem solving

## Languages

- English Fluent
- German Conversational